LUCYLLE MAKACHIA

Residency: Nairobi, Kenya

Email: <u>lucylemakachia@gmail.com</u> | Mobile: +254 717 889532 LinkedIn: <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/lucylle-makachia/</u>

Executive Summary

A young professional with experience in information management. Have accumulated skills in data research, entry, collection, cleaning, analysis, visualization and presentation including dashboard development. Highly curious with excellent problem solving skills essential in dissenting complex datasets and interpreting them into simple digestible nature.

Key Skills and Competencies

Information Management | Data Management | Research | Analysis | Reporting | Partnerships | Grants Management | Dashboard | Humanitarian Preparedness and Response | English | ArcGIS | QGIS | Power BI | Microsoft Excel | Microsoft Word | Kobo Collect

Professional Experience

UN Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs Volunteer - Humanitarian Situation & Needs Analysis

Geneva (Remote) Nov 2023 - Jan 2024

Research & Data Collection

- Monitored over 30 news sources, press releases, social media outlets, and websites, tracking hostilities and responses in oPT, resulting in the identification and categorization of 2,800+ data points using the DEEP model, ensuring a 98% accuracy rate in reports.
- Compiled geo-coordinates for 10+ key facilities (schools, hospitals, and camps), improving response planning and resource allocation efficiency

Data Quality & Teamwork

• Ensured data quality of 500+ information entries onto the data platform by collaborating with 10 team members to ensure accuracy and completeness.

Analysis & Reporting

- Transcribed about 30 minutes of video and audio materials, extracting relevant information for analysis.
- Created 3 summary analysis reports on the health situation and response in oPT, supporting decision-making by humanitarian actors.

UN Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs Information Management Intern

Nairobi, Kenya April - October 2023

GIS & Mapping

- Employed ArcGIS to develop 4 reference maps, with administrative boundaries, roads and hydrological features, enhancing field visits and stakeholder meeting presentations.
- Used QGIS to merge 3 vector administrative boundaries and convert the Json files into GeoJson format, reducing manual processing time.

Data Visualization & Dashboard Development

- Updated 5 Adobe Illustrator dashboard reports with information on surge support, humanitarian operational presence and infographics such as maps, icons, pie and bar charts, boosting data accessibility for stakeholders.
- Developed 1 interactive Power BI dashboard, with a brief narrative, map, icons, line and pie charts, highlighting 4 humanitarian figures, improving access to colleagues.

Data Analysis & Management

- Researched on 4 key humanitarian figures, such as refugees, IDPs, food security and the occurrence of disease cases, collected and organized the information on MS Excel worksheets, resulting in improved data readiness for reporting.
- Crafted 3 data collecting forms in MS Excel with the purpose of acquiring partner information regarding their operational presence, contact details, relief supplies, and warehouse capacity, all geared toward improving 2023 El Niño preparedness.
- Trained on data statistics creating formulas and visual graphics like pivot tables, line and bar graphs on MS Excel.
- Developed a streamlined process for data extraction from Kobo Toolbox, ensuring accurate and efficient transfer of information to MS Excel.

Administrative Support

• Managed the ReliefWeb Response meeting calendar for 2023 Sudan conflict, scheduling and documenting 20+ high-level coordination meetings, improving cross-team collaboration.

Presentation & Documentation

- Created 2 MS PowerPoint presentations (mid-point and final) highlighting internship's objective, tasks, achievements, challenges faced and future goals.
- Compiled 20+ Needs Assessments reports into a common MS SharePoint folder, extract key information and stored them in a MS Excel worksheet and Google Sheet, for sharing with partners.

Regen Organics (Sanergy) Grants Research and Development Fellow

Nairobi, Kenya October 2022 - April 2023

Research & Grant Management

• Conducted regular self-directed research from online sources to identify 25+ potential grant funding partners for different work streams.

- Spearheaded fundraising by writing 10 opportunity analysis reports, highlighting application requirements, budgets, timelines and compliance requirements, for new grant opportunities and presenting to the team.
- Supported in collecting 10+ research papers/findings from international organizations and governments used for developing concept notes and project proposals.
- Trained on the grant development process, using the USAID Africa Trade and Investment (ATI) program.

Database Management

• Coordinated the progression of 25+ grant opportunities through the MS Excel pipeline database, including inputting grantor data and providing regular status updates.

Industry Analysis

• Analyzed 10+ industry trends and developments, from blog posts, events or forums, developing new research strategies that expanded funding opportunities.

United Nations Environment Programme (UNEP) Programme Management Intern

Nairobi, Kenya April - October 2022

Research & Partnership Development

- Conducted in-depth research and analysis of areas of collaboration, 100+ partnership opportunities and potential donor funding in the private sector.
- Initiated the processing of 5+ comprehensive partnership procedures, including conducting partner validation, reviewing due diligence assessments (used reports from RepRisk and Sustainalytics), writing risk and strategy assessments on the organization's profile.
- Established and maintained a centralized database to track 100+ potential and established partnerships.
- Drafted 2 case studies and 2 background papers, using MS Word based on online sources, on potential funding partners i.e., on foundations and philanthropists. (Link tosamplework:

https://drive.google.com/file/d/1PyZMdFn2cYTIf7srWSosAowPBDOTzWCo/view?usp=drive_link)

Administrative Support & Team work

• Collaborated with 2 cross-functional team members as a notetaker, ensuring all meeting minutes and action points were distributed on time.

Data Collection & Coordination

• Coordinated the collection, analysis, and synthesis of data from diverse sources, including online sources and expert meetings, to support strategic planning efforts and improve decision-making processes.

Reporting & Documentation

• Created 1 MS PowerPoint workflow presentation highlighting proposed steps when approaching potential funding partners - foundations and philanthropies.

Systems Design

• Brainstormed on 8 features to include in the proposed Customer Relationship Management (CRM) system.

Monitoring & Evaluation (M&E)

• Learned how to employ Monitoring & Evaluation (M&E) techniques, to manage, track and report on project deliverables and milestones.

National Environment Management Authority (NEMA) Compliance Attaché

Kiambu, Kenya June - Nov 2021

Office Coordination & Documentation

• Improved office coordination by managing the receipt and dispatch of 30+ environmental reports and licenses.

Fieldwork & Compliance

• Maintained compliance with development policies by conducting 2 site inspections, recording observations and advocating for improvements.

Data Analysis & Reporting

- Increased project efficiency by organizing and analyzing desk and field data research on 30+ development projects.
- Maintained accurate and up-to-date of up to 100 records by managing the file and registry maintenance of received, pending, and processed reports and licenses.

Client Relationship Management

• Strengthened 30+ client relationships by providing timely and clear communication on report and license processing progress and responding to inquiries.

Education

The Catholic University of Eastern Africa
Bachelors of Environmental Planning and Management

Nairobi, Kenya Sept 2017 - Oct 2021

Certification

UNEP Learning Management System

Results-Based Programme and Project Management

Online course May 2022

LinkedIn Learning

Become a Data Analyst

Online course January 2021

Modcom Institute of Technology

Python, Data Science and Machine Learning

Nairobi, Kenya January 2020

Publications

Featured in: Africa Business Case Study Handbook - Volume 5